Thank for you choosing to fly
with Oberth Aerospace today.
We departed from
the Bangkok airport on...
2068.
The accident with the Alnair 8
suborbital passenger liner...
...focused public attention on the problem
of cosmic junk. Space debris.
Abandoned artificial satellites.
Tanks jettisoned from shuttles.
Refuse generated during
space station construction.
This debris is traveling around the Earth
at speeds approaching 8 km/s.
Should this debris collide with a spacecraft,
it could result in a terrible accident.
And so, to prevent such a tragedy
from ever happening again,
...as well as for the sake of
further space development,
...disposal of this debris
has become a necessity.
This is a story of the people
who live in such a time as this.
Outside the Atmosphere
GO-S09, routing from
exposed area to Bay Five.
Main umbilical,
connection complete.
I'm in space...
I finally got a
space assignment!
Next stop, Technora Corporation
office block.
Zero-G... Satellite orbit...
Astronauts!
Oh, right.
That's our mascot character...
GO-S15, this is
Seven Departure.
Downlinking vector and window to
Navigation Data Matrix. Complete.
Excuse me!
I am Ai Tanabe, newly assigned to
Second Department, Debris Section!
Age 20, single, Japanese!
I look forward to working with you!
MO-L258, this is
Seven Delivery.
Um...
At least learn where things are in the company.
This is Control Section.
Huh? It is?
Oh, I'm sorry!
Claire, we'll wait until we get instructions
from INTO to deal with that plate.
Understood, sir.
I'm really sorry...
Thank you.
Good grief... You must be a new
recruit for the Half Section.
Half Section?
No, ma'am, Debris Section.
Like I said,
Half Section.
If you're looking for Half Section, take the
company elevator all the way to the bottom.
What were you thinking,
Tanabe?
"Control Section" is written there
as plain as day!
You could've said something,
you know...
That's what you get for trying
to make a grand entrance!
Say, wasn't that the guy who gave the speech
at our company welcoming ceremony?
Right, he's the
department manager.
One point deduction,
looks like.
It's not like my workshop grades
were all that great...
Look out! Sheesh, this is why
you're at the bottom of the class.
Maybe, but she came in second at the Technora
company dance competition, remember?
Dance?
Sure, you remember.
The one where you were
supposed to express...
...your Technora company spirit
through an original dance.
Only two of us entered.
Oh, really?
Who in their right mind would sign up
for something that embarrassing?
I'm amazed you entered!
Look, I joined by walking in off the street
and I've got no connections,
...but I wanted to try to go
into space, so I signed up for it.
See you later, Tanabe. Aerospace Section
is to the left, so this is my stop.
Maintenance Section, too.
I guess this is goodbye
for now.
That's the elevator that will
take you down, Tanabe.
Come on,
I'm not a kid!
Be careful.
Of what?
If you run into any drama queens
or dirty old men, don't fight back.
'Cause you always act
before thinking.
She doesn't pay attention
to her surroundings, either.
I don't?
No, you don't.
See you
at lunch, then.
Remember, Debris Section
is downstairs.
Lay off!
Debris Section is all
the way at the bottom...
All the way at the bottom...
All the way at the bottom is Debris Section.
Yep, this is it,
all right.
Starting today,
this is my workplace.
Let's do it!
Excuse me! I've just been assigned to
Second Department, Debris... Section?
I-I've made a mistake!
Pardon me!
But this is Debris Section...
Um...
I'm sorry to keep bothering you,
but where is Debris...
I've had it up to here with their
"Half Section" crap!
Dammit, Chief, how come we always
play second fiddle to Control Section?!
Well, they have a bigger staff
than we do.
Those guys don't even
use spacesuits!
An astronaut...
A real astronaut!
Huh? Who are you?
Diapers?
Hey, don't blow people off
when they're talking to you.
M-My name is Tanabe!
I'm a new employee.
You are?
Come to think of it, Human Resources said
something about us getting somebody new...
Hey, I'm your senior. What's the big idea,
running away from your Sempai?
B-But, well, put something on
down there!
Down where?
I am wearing something.
But they're diapers!
All astronauts wear diapers!
You should know that!
Stay away!
Please.
Say what?! Who do you
think you are, rookie?!
But...
When you're out in the field,
this is what you wear!
I'm gonna knock some real-world
sense into you, so get ready!
But couldn't this be thought of
as sexual harassment?
Sexual harassment?!
You aren't going to sue, are you?
Chief, call Legal Affairs at once!
Please, don't go public
with this!
Something's on me!
Get it off!
Hey, what's the big idea?!
Hey! For the last time,
no cigarettes!
Hey, come back!
Come back!
Over here, miss,
over here.
This is Philippe Myers, assistant section
manager for Debris Section.
In other words,
he's the top dog here.
I look forward to working
with you, sir.
Of course.
Same here.
And I'm the supervisor assistant,
Arvind Lavie.
I'm number two
around here!
It's a pleasure
to meet you!
Oh, this?
This is for the send off and welcoming
party at General Affairs later.
Really?
The important thing is that
you're a company girl now,
...so make sure you remember
the pecking order, okay?
Excuse me?
Greet the most important
person first.
R-Right.
Still, I'm glad you're here. It's been
three years since our last newcomer.
To be honest, there's no money
to be made in collecting debris.
So our section's performance
rates at the bottom each year.
But it's like that at the debris sections
of every other company, Chief!
We're the bottom
of the barrel.
You see this room?
It used to be a cargo bay.
Anyway, don't expect
to move up in the world.
The work's hard, it's dangerous, our budget
is a joke, and then there's the diapers...
Hachi!
What if she quits?!
If that's enough to make her quit,
we're better off without her.
Even if there's no money in it,
it's a job that needs to be done.
Oh, you're not out of the
astronaut academy, huh?
Um...
Fee Carmichael. I captain
the debris recovery ship Toy Box.
Yuri!
This is my first mate,
Yuri Mihairokoh.
Pleased to meet you.
That's Edelgard Rivera.
She's a temp staffer.
She takes care of
the office work for us.
She's a temp?
I wish they'd send us
temp superiors like her, too...
Fee! Criticism of
your superiors... -
- should be used
in moderation.
And last but not least,
that's Hachirota Hoshino.
We call him
Hachimaki.
Like a hachimaki headband?
It fits.
Get off my case! I didn't
give myself the nickname!
Come on, play nice.
I'm teaming you up with her, after all.
Why?!
She works EVA, too.
Go over to Materials Section and
get her fitted for a spacesuit, okay?
What's "EVA"
stand for again?
I thought I was an extravehicular
activity worker...
It means
the same thing!
O-Oh, of course.
I look forward to working with you.
Geez, I can't believe these
general hires...
Okay, all done.
You can go now.
But I still haven't...
If we custom-made every spacesuit,
we'd run ourselves into the red.
Customizing parts of them
is good enough.
We have one-size-fits-all spacesuits
in the next room, so go put one on.
Yes, ma'am!
Hey, wait!
Ma'am?
We can't have you leaving your
oversized garbage lying around.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll take it off your hands.
How does it look?
Just great!
Nice body!
Okay, we'll run face panel tests next.
You know how to do that, right?
Yes, sir. I learned that
during our workshops.
All right, let's start with axis alignment.
Try setting your artificial horizon to Earth.
Yes, sir!
Man, this is all
Control Section's fault...
Hey, Hachimaki.
Hey.
What are you guys gonna do about
that debris that everybody's talking about?
Beats me. Sounds like the top brass
are still fighting it out.
Okay, time for your next stop,
diaper girl!
Come on, Sempai,
don't shout it out!
This is the real thing...
Well, that oughta
do it.
Sempai, that's one more
than what's on our list.
Having an extra
won't kill us, right?
We can't! We have
to do this by the book!
Of all the stupid...
It's on the next shelf over!
Please return it to where you got it!
You're taking things
too seriously.
You don't take them
seriously enough!
Yeah, yeah, yeah...
You work real hard and be serious
enough for the both of us, okay?
Oh, right. Maybe I'll put in
some food, too...
Is everyone else
like this?
Huh?
I always thought that astronauts
would be more amazing.
That they'd always be restrained,
and brave, and earnest...
In this day and age?
What are you talking about?
This is 2075, you know. Things aren't like
when man first set foot on the moon.
Hell, they changed the instant
you managed to join the company.
Well, you have a point...
But it's kinda different from...
Okay, we'll need
these, too.
What's that?
What, you've never seen
a porno mag before?
That's not what I mean! Why would
we need something like that?!
We need it. Depending on the job, men and
women can be together for days at a time.
If we don't take matters into our own hands,
it could lead to trouble, right?
Here. This one's
for you.
What a disaster...
Unlike you guys, I'm stuck with
cigarettes, animals, magic tricks,
...and a guy in diapers with a knack
for sexual harassment.
I'm not surprised.
That's Half Section for you.
Half Section?
Now that you mention it, someone
in Control Section called them...
They say that our Debris Section
plan got held up somehow,
...so they only have half the personnel
they were supposed to.
They're a section with only half
a staff, so "Half Section."
And they're supposed to be
half-trained, half-assed,
...half-cocked, half-hearted,
half-crazy, and...
I'm gonna
hang in there!
Oh, really?
They're not gonna beat me!
Not Half Section, and not even diaper man!
W-Well, give it
your best shot.
Yeah, let me
at 'em!
I'll do it myself,
I'll do it myself!
Pipe down.
Don't tell me you're still mad
about earlier!
Of course I am!
You hit me as hard as you could!
Hachimaki, all our departure
paperwork is finished.
Right.
Stop horsing around, Tanabe.
Hurry it up.
You heard her.
We're really going out
into space?
We can't do our job if we don't
go out into the field, right?
But I just got here today!
I don't know anything about ships!
In that case, you'll be fine. This ship
has been flying for over 30 years.
What?! The DS-12
is that old?!
Toy Box.
No self-respecting sailor
calls his ship by its number!
Somebody help me!
DS-12, this is ISPV-7.
Comm system multi-channel check.
You copy?
I copy.
DS-12, this is ISPV-7.
This is an abort indicator test.
I copy. Check nominal.
I knew it, they're different
when they're on the job...
DS-12, shipboard pressure confirmed.
Now switching over power source.
Hey, rookie! Go get a barf bag
and stand by!
I'm already taking
motion sickness medicine!
Seven, this is DS-12.
Power source switchover complete.
Avionics and all electrical systems are nominal.
IMU orientation determination...
Please rest assured, sir. We will dispose
of the plate as waste debris.
Yes, sir.
Main umbilical,
separate.
Separation complete.
You copy?
I copy.
Taking free.
DS-12, this is Seven.
Establishing datalink via Navstar.
Datalink confirmed.
We will be making orbital plane change
using ME to reach transfer orbit...
What do you think?
Cool, huh?
It sure is! It's way prettier than
looking at it on a shuttle!
S-Sempai, this, uh...
What is it?
Oh, that broke off this time?
THIS time?!
Well, this ship is a heap,
after all.
Are you kidding me?
Are you kidding me?!
Wouldn't that get us
into trouble?
Vega Corporation uses an elephant
in their logo, right?
So why not make one using our own logo?
To show our love for our company.
Brilliant, Chief!
I'll take that idea and run with it!
It's a company banquet, after all.
We have to pay attention to these things.
In that case, let's make a Mr. Nora
out of recycled paper!
Great idea!
We're contributing to society!
The Debris Duo...
For us, spacesuits
are our uniform.
Become so familiar with it that you can
put it on even if you're half asleep.
You copy?
It means, "Do you get it?"
I understand.
I mean, I copy.
Are you two ready?
We'll be coming up on the plate soon.
Plate?
Our debris for this job is a memorial plate
that was sent up 20 years ago,
...asking that the children of Mananga
be allowed to live in peace.
Its orbit intersects that of
an artificial satellite.
Your first job is to scrap it
by dropping it towards Earth.
Scrap it? You mean
we're not retrieving it?
Debris that can't be used as raw material
gets dropped and burned.
But it's a plate
that's a message of peace!
As if something like that
could ever create peace...
The desire to create peace and cherish it
is what will bring peace to the world!
Maybe a diaper man like you wouldn't
understand that, Sempai.
Geez... Would you listen to that naive crap
you're spouting, rookie?
When it comes to doing what's right,
there's no sempais or rookies!
And anyway, you...
Okay, that's enough
of that.
Tanabe, I can understand what
you're saying, but this is our job.
That plate may be important,
but so is that satellite.
But we don't have to
scrap it...
Orders from
the bosses.
Somebody has to do
the job.
Getting rid of debris in orbit
is vital to space development.
Understand?
Yes, ma'am.
I understand, but...
It's just not right.
There's no love!
Debris collector ship DS-12
has arrived at target point.
T-minus 58 minutes to contact between
the plate and the INTO satellite.
INTO is starting
to get pretty jumpy.
The disposal order
has been sent.
I'll check each stage of the operation during
our regularly scheduled communications.
Very well.
Um, Sempai?
I'm a little scared...
Like they say, the best time to learn
to swim is when you're drowning.
Don't say that!
I don't wanna drown in space!
Do you think she's
going to work out?
Well, she's taking workshops,
and we'll be in trouble...
...if we don't make her
useful ASAP, right?
I guess you're right. It's just a drop,
and Mr. Hoshino's with her.
So, what's this satellite that the plate
is gonna collide with?
Didn't you read
the mission profile?
I didn't get
the mission profile!
Oh, you didn't?
It's INTO's Dario-1 4.
Dario?
But isn't that a...
Yep, a military bird.
It monitors the Earth
from space,
...and keeps an eye out to see if some
country somewhere is misbehaving.
So if some country tries to expand its military,
INTO will come storming in, right?
They talk about keeping the peace and
liberation, but they're really just looking out for...
STOP!
What the hell do you think you're doing?!
You rank amateur!
But it's a military satellite, Sempai!
It's a tool for war!
We can't scrap a symbol of peace
to save something like that!
What are you saying?
One's a functional satellite, and the other's
a plate that's just floating there!
How can you
compare the two?!
There's nothing to compare!
Which is more important, peace or war?!
Listen up!
We're debris collectors!
We get rid of the plate as part
of our job, and that's that!
Then the satellite ought to be hit
by the plate and be destroyed!
What the hell
are you saying?!
If we did that,
it'd just make more debris!
H-Hey, wait!
My feet...
I'm drowning!
Geez, at least learn
your suit's halt code!
Hey, we got work
to do!
Even if this is our job,
it's just not right!
I thought astronauts were supposed to be free
of countries and gravity and all that other stuff!
Give the noble daydreams a rest,
you preachy rookie.
Astronauts are wage slaves
just like any other!
It's because of that that everybody
calls you the Half Section!
You've got to set
your goals higher!
Complete!
Target point reached.
But this is INTO's logo...
This is the
memorial plate.
"In 2055, peace was preserved in Mananga
through the efforts of INTO."
"An evil regime was opposed in order to
establish a foothold for freedom and justice..."
Big talk, considering that they're the ones who
started the conflict in Mananga in the first place.
What the heck is this?
This is a symbol of peace?
This is just
INTO propaganda!
Well, it's true that they can't afford
to have this brought back, not now.
Hell, our country's in INTO now, too,
so I guess it can't be helped.
I'm sorry about what I said.
Please go ahead and drop this thing.
Hey, that's your job, too.
Forget it. You just sit there.
You copy?
I copy...
DS-12, this is ISPV-7.
Please report operation status.
We've cleared up through phase 9.
Standing by for de-orbit burn.
Um... Sempai?
It's been 15 minutes.
We're way behind schedule.
Oh, I'm sorry. You're going to do it,
aren't you, Sempai?
Rookie.
Yes?
Why'd you come
into space?
Well, um... When I was getting close to
graduation time, I started to get curious.
I wanted to learn
what my limits were.
What kind of person I was.
How big a mark I could leave on the world.
So I...
But I guess I'm not
cut out for space...
What did I
come here for?
What did I hope
to accomplish?
All I did was prove that I'm earthbound
right down to the core.
Tanabe.
Tanabe, you read me?
Fee?
Watch the plate
as it's going down.
Pretty...
The children of Mananga
are seeing that.
The course it's on should
take it right over Mananga.
And with their weather today, they should
have a nice, clear view of it.
If it can bring happiness
to the children of Mananga,
...even if only for a brief moment, regardless of
the ulterior motives of the people who built it,
...even a piece of debris like that
has some value, don't you think?
You waited for more than 15 minutes
so you could do this?
Rookie.
Y-Yes, sir?
We're heading back to Toy Box.
You copy?
I copy!
ISPV-7, this DS-12
Phase clear.
DS-12, this is Seven.
Dario-1 4 orbital clearance confirmed.
Mission complete.
I copy. Now engaging return mode
to head back to Seven.
Hachimaki Sempai! What do you mean,
"Special Excess Allowance"?!
Give it a rest!
If you're out in space for longer than your
maximum time allowed, you get extra pay!
You got paid, too,
didn't you?
Is that why you waited
for more than 15 minutes?!
What other reason
would there be?
You mean you didn't do it
to give the children of Mananga...
...a shooting star of hope
as a present?!
What's that sap you're spouting,
diaper girl?
Don't you talk down to me,
diaper boy!
Is that any way to talk
to your senior?!
Seniors or juniors don't
enter into it!
- Don't you have any tact in you?!
- Give your superior enough time to have a smoke in peace, okay?
Then stop pointing
your finger at people!
Oh. Sorry about that...
But those two things are...
Totally different?
Of course they are!
Don't you get it, Sempai?!
Who do you think you are,
you rookie?!
What's that?
"Idea Notebook for Obtaining
a Spaceship of My Own."
Excuse me?
Apparently, he had it even before
he joined the company.
Sempai!
This is one time when running away
or failing isn't an option!
It ain't an option!
Can I really do it?